Now that we know that you can access
attributes from the HTML and you can set
attributes of the HTML, the sky is the
limit. Um, for example, what I want to
do here is I want to take this input and
I want to change the color of the body
based on what color they picked in the
color picker.
So if I want to do that, I need to write
this change color function. So const
change color
and it helps if you don't have a typo.
Okay, so now we have a function. If we
want to change the color, then we need
to access the value of this input and we
need to change the color of the body
tag. How do we change the color of the
body tag without um JavaScript? Well,
the way you do that is you'd say style
background color red. And that would set
the background color of the body to red.
Well, if we want to access this object,
then we need to use the DOM. So, we'll
say document.getelement
by id and main. And we want to set its
style attribute to be something. Now, we
could set it to say background color
red, but what I want to do is I actually
want to just use because style is a
JavaScript object, I can type dot. And
now I can access all of the attributes
directly. So, I'm going to set the
background color
equal to well, now what color do I want
to set it to? Well, I want to set it to
this input tag. So, um, I could do this
all on one line, but for ease of reading
my code, I'm going to say
document.getelement
by ID color picker.
And then I'm going to access the value
of that. And I'm going to say
let chosen color equal grab that color
picker value. And then I want to set the
background color of my body tag. I want
to set it equal to my chosen color. So,
if we save that and we come over here,
we've got our little color picker here
and we could choose this color and it
updates. Um, we could use the dropper
and choose the top menu
and it updates. Um,
we could put in a hex value. Um,
and now our page updates. And so that is
how you can um update the visual display
based on user input.